<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home</title>
    <link>http://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 18:34:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim</title>
      <link>http://example.org/notes/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 18:34:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/notes/vim/</guid>
      <description>Vim with Netwr let g:netrw_banner = 0 let g:netrw_liststyle = 3 let g:netrw_browse_split = 4 let g:netrw_altv = 1 let g:netrw_winsize = 25 augroup ProjectDrawer autocmd! autocmd VimEnter * :Vexplore augroup END Vim scripts Reference https://shapeshed.com/vim-netrw/
https://learnvimscriptthehardway.stevelosh.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MyTools</title>
      <link>http://example.org/notes/mytools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 17:41:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/notes/mytools/</guid>
      <description>This page contains the list of tools I used in my laptop. It was used to set a ready-to-use host from IAC.
A. OS I am taking here the case of Ubuntu, but this should work with similar distros of the same family.
B. Tools  Update  $ sudo apt update -y $ sudo apt install git vim -y $ git config --global user.email percyyperezdante@gmail.com </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General</title>
      <link>http://example.org/devopssec/3h/general/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 14:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/devopssec/3h/general/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  Initial general references  Cyberthreat in real time Threat map check point EC Council Code of ethics Technet evaluation center    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CloudSecurity</title>
      <link>http://example.org/devops/cloudsecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 18:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/devops/cloudsecurity/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to coud security Cloud deployment methods Software delivery mechanism  SaaS: Hands-off approach, where all hardware, software and security controls are managed by the provider, e.g. email. PaaS: Where you place your own source code on the top of the provider&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure or platform, e.g. Heroku. IaaS: Where you build your own infrastrucuture and deploy your code on the top.  Challenges and barriers when you move to the cloud include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible</title>
      <link>http://example.org/notes/ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 15:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/notes/ansible/</guid>
      <description>General Ansible cnetralizes model:
  Adhoc example:
$ ansible -m copy -a &amp;#34;src=orignalFile.txt dest=finalFile.txt&amp;#34; --check --diff localhost Where
 Check = to run in dry mode Diff = Shows the difference before and after apply ansible &amp;ldquo;copy&amp;rdquo; is a module, list of all ansible modules in here &amp;ldquo;m&amp;rdquo; module name &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo; arguments  More examples   Playbook   A playbook uses a Yaml file as main place to read from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codecommitcmd</title>
      <link>http://example.org/devops/aws/devopseng/codecommitcmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 11:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/devops/aws/devopseng/codecommitcmd/</guid>
      <description>Below are suggested steps to work with CodeCommit from Command line
  NOTE   You need to have AWSCodeCommitPowerUser  or similar in your AWS account profile in the section Permission policies*     Be sure you have a public key upload into your IAM profile
  To check if you have already one or more public keys in AIM
$ aws iam list-ssh-public-keys { &amp;#34;SSHPublicKeys&amp;#34;: [] }   If you have not any public key updated, then update one:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIAutomation</title>
      <link>http://example.org/devops/aws/devopseng/ciautomation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 17:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/devops/aws/devopseng/ciautomation/</guid>
      <description>II Designinh a Source control strategy with CodeCommit   Devops covers at least the following areas:
 Development workflows Test, build, and deploy applications Infrastructure as a code    Why AWS
 AWS is public cloud leader AWS is a full platform of integration with other services.    What is Devops
 It is a blanket term for tooling, practices, and ideas that allow organization sto build better software - faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoreServices</title>
      <link>http://example.org/devops/aws/cloudpractitioner/coreservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 18:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/devops/aws/cloudpractitioner/coreservices/</guid>
      <description>Methods to interact to AWS   AWS console
 Includes Mobule app Good for testing services or simple tests    AWS CLI
 Includes: Java, .net, Node.js, JS, PHP, Python, Ruby, Go, C++ automation    AWS SDK
 automation use it when you want to integreat to your app    AWS console   Two types of user: ROOT USRE and IAM user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://example.org/devops/aws/cloudpractitioner/fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 10:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/devops/aws/cloudpractitioner/fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Main topics:   Creating an account
  Examining traditional data center challenges:
 Large up-front investment Difficult to predict future traffic or demand Slow deploy of new data centers and servers Maintain data centers is expensive You own all security and compliance burden with all data centers    Benefits of cloud computing
 Trade capital expense for variable expenses: you pay what you use Scaling Stop to guess future needed capacity, traffic Speed and agility Stop spend money for maintenance Go global in minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restful</title>
      <link>http://example.org/notes/restful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 09:35:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/notes/restful/</guid>
      <description>Design tips  URI format:  URI = scheme &amp;quot;://&amp;quot; authority &amp;quot;/&amp;quot; path [ &amp;quot;?&amp;quot; query] [&amp;quot;#&amp;quot; fragment&amp;quot;] URI = http://myserver.com/mypath?query=1#document   General rules for URI formating:
 A forward slash / is used to indicate a hierarchical relationship between resources A trailing forward slash / should not be included in URIs Hyphens - should be used to improve readability Underscores _ should not be used in URIs Lowercase lette    URI path design</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mypostmortem</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sre/mypostmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 11:19:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/sre/mypostmortem/</guid>
      <description>Random notes  Expose your code for one day to everyone. Ask people to execute disaster revocery of everything once or twice a year. blameless I do not think is a way to avoid future mistakes, I think it is a way to save time and effort, thefore reduce costs. We should test our selves at least once a year. to see how if we are ready or notfor disasters Postmorten of the month?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jfrog</title>
      <link>http://example.org/notes/jfrog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 14:09:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/notes/jfrog/</guid>
      <description>1. How to install a local Jfrog (open source) The following shows how to install a local Jfrog (OSS) in a Linux-base host.
 Open https://jfrog.com/open-source/#artifactory Select the OS you are working with: Linux, Windows or Mac and click on &amp;ldquo;Click here to Download&amp;rdquo;  In our case we could directly download the tar file for Linux:
$ mkdir myJfrog $ cd myJfrog $ wget https://api.bintray.com/content/jfrog/artifactory/org/artifactory/oss/jfrog-artifactory-oss/$latest/jfrog-artifactory-oss-$latest-linux.tar.gz?bt_package=jfrog-artifactory-oss $ ls -tlr total 811768 -rw-rw-r-- 1 percy percy 831242240 Aug 26 17:28 jfrog-artifactory-oss-7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sre/review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:04:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/sre/review/</guid>
      <description>This section contains reviews or summaries from exisitng literature.
1. SQL is no excuse to avoid devops @article{limoncelli2018sql, title={SQL is no excuse to avoid DevOps}, author={Limoncelli, Thomas A}, journal={Communications of the ACM}, volume={62}, number={1}, pages={46--49}, year={2018}, publisher={ACM New York, NY, USA} } Automation and a little discipline allow better testing, shorter release cycles, and reduced business risk.
Previous articles:
 “The Small Batches Principle,”Communications, July 2016), when something is risky there is a natural inclination to seek to do it less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myapproach</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sre/myapproach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 08:40:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/sre/myapproach/</guid>
      <description>What is SRE  SRE measures how reliable my serivice is from my customer&amp;rsquo;s perspective, not from my perspective. It seems most of the talks use current or historic data, logs, Why we do not estimate future data then ?  The reason is that usually you take generated logs, so it is hard to have a real-time observations. How to have real-time observations? how to estimate the future?    SLO  Defines a threshold, max or min value, for an SLI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRECON 2019</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sre/online/srecon2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 16:52:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/sre/online/srecon2019/</guid>
      <description>1. The SRE I Aspire to be by Yaniv Aknin at SRECON 2019  Yaniv A. is GCP quantitative reliability lead. SRE skill is the ability to measure or translate to numbers ( quantify ) SRE includes: &amp;ldquo;measurably optimse reliability vs cost&amp;rdquo; It is important to trade Operations and Reliability How can we build a more reliable logical disk? then we do not need to increase operations due to failure. One solution as use RAIDs, but cost more and more complexity!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypto</title>
      <link>http://example.org/notes/crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 22:11:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/notes/crypto/</guid>
      <description>General  DES; The Data Encryption Standard uses a key of 56bits and a block size of 64 buts. It is not recommended, and insted you can consider other approaches such as AES, Salsa20.:w   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking</title>
      <link>http://example.org/devops/gcp/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 09:29:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/devops/gcp/networking/</guid>
      <description>VPC Virtual Private Cloud VPC is a set of GCP objects, such as:
  Project
 Associated to services and networks Organize infrastructure resources Link objects and services with billing Contain networks, default up to 5 It containt entire networks    Network: can be shared with other projects or peered, are global, and no ip address range
 Default  Every project one subnet per region Default firewall rules   Auto  Default network One subnet per region Regional IP allocation Fixed /20 subnet per region Expandable to /16   Custom  No default subnets created Full control of IP ranges Regional IP allocation Expandable to any RFC 1918 size    To connect to a on-premises network you can use a VPN gateway service from VPC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell</title>
      <link>http://example.org/notes/shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 11:52:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/notes/shell/</guid>
      <description>1. Sending message to pts terminal # List of opened terminals. percy@prec:~$ ls -tlr /dev/pts/ total 0 c--------- 1 root root 5, 2 May 21 06:18 ptmx crw--w---- 1 percy tty 136, 2 May 21 11:36 2 crw--w---- 1 percy tty 136, 0 May 21 11:52 0 crw--w---- 1 percy tty 136, 3 May 21 11:53 3 crw--w---- 1 percy tty 136, 4 May 21 11:53 4 crw--w---- 1 percy tty 136, 6 May 21 11:53 6 crw--w---- 1 percy tty 136, 5 May 21 11:53 5 percy@prec:~$ echo &amp;#34;How are you ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://example.org/notes/kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 15:12:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/notes/kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Reference The following notes were extracted, adjusted or extended from the following references.
 Kubernetes book by Nigel Poulton Kubernetes setup  Kubernetes the hard way Kubernetes network administraion  Google Kubernetes Engine: GKE docs AWS Elastic Container Service for Kubernetes EKS Kubectl docs  General   Kubernetes is a container orchestrator, which means to maintain, manage and support container that run applications. Kubernetes also manage workload placement, it offers an infrastructure abstraction and maintains a desire state of the infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go</title>
      <link>http://example.org/notes/go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 11:04:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/notes/go/</guid>
      <description>References The following notes were extracted, adjusted or extended from the following references.
 Go mastering by Mihalis Tsoukalos  General 1. Go inserts only a semicolon at the end of a &amp;ldquo;{&amp;quot;
func main() { // &amp;lt;-- this will trigger error .... } func main(){ // &amp;lt;-- this will NOT trigger error .... } 2. Install and clean packages
$ go get -v github.com/mastsoud/go/package_name ..... $ go clean -i -v -x package_name $ rm -rf ~/go/src/github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://example.org/devops/gcp/fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 11:06:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/devops/gcp/fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Introduction GCP offers four main services:
- Compute - Storage - Big data - Machine learning  The fundamentals course covers mainly the first two plus networking.
Cloud computing is an on-demand infrastrucuture available under the following characteristics:
- Compute resouces on-demand self-service: no human intervention - Access from anywhere in the internet - Resource pooling: GCP provides share-base resources - Rapid elasiticity: Get more resources quickly as needed - Measured service: pay for what you consume or use  There are serveral GCP computing services, such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRE MMR Week4</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sre/online/sre-mmr-week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 23:02:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/sre/online/sre-mmr-week4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRE MMR Week3</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sre/online/sre-mmr-week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 23:02:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/sre/online/sre-mmr-week3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRE MMR Week2</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sre/online/sre-mmr-week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 23:02:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/sre/online/sre-mmr-week2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRE MMR Week1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sre/online/sre-mmr-week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 22:54:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/sre/online/sre-mmr-week1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to SRE How does SRE differ from Devops? Devops and SRE point to similar goals, which is break down organizational barriers to deliver software features faster.
Traditionally, developers are responsable for features and operations for stability. Developers want to move faster to release new features and operations want to move slow to keep all service stable. As a commong results, tension between teams appears during realease times. Devops and SRE practices aim to break downs this tensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sre/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 12:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/sre/references/</guid>
      <description>This page present a list of references related to SRE.
Books   Beyer, B., Jones, C., Petoff, J. and Murphy, N.R., 2016. Site Reliability Engineering: How Google Runs Production Systems. &amp;quot; O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media, Inc.&amp;quot;.
 A online available version can be read from here.    Beyer, B., Murphy, N.R., Rensin, D.K., Kawahara, K. and Thorne, S., 2018. The site reliability workbook: Practical ways to implement SRE. &amp;quot; O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media, Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>http://example.org/tools/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 16:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/tools/installation/</guid>
      <description>This page presents suggestions on how to install tools of interest. It is ordered alphabetically.
A G   GO
 $ git clone https://github.com/golang/go.git $ cd go/src $ ./all.bash # &amp;lt;-- This should generate ../bin/go file. $ cd .. $ export GOPATH=`pwd` # &amp;lt;-- Add this to your profile such as ~/.bashrc $ cd bin $ export GOBIN=`pwd` # &amp;lt;-- Add this to your profile such as ~/.bashrc $ go version    GIT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NManet</title>
      <link>http://example.org/research/nmanet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 22:51:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/research/nmanet/</guid>
      <description>Very brief overview NDN for MANETs approach, represented as nMANET, aims to offer an alternative perspective on how the characteristics of NDN can be utilised to solve the limitations of MANETs. nMANET has its roots in Named Data Network NDN, an instance of Content Centric Networks CCN. In contrast with traditional TCP/IP networks, CCN enables content addressing instead of host based communication, and secures the content instead of securing the communication channel between hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Images</title>
      <link>http://example.org/devops/images/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 17:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/devops/images/</guid>
      <description>This page presents a set of templates to build images through tools such as packer. The content of these templates is the result of a combination of available resources online.
Packer This sections present cases about how to build linux-base images. More details in the Ajayu github repository.
 Oracle Linux 6.10 using a DVD .iso file. Jenkins and Capistrano V2 base on OL6. It is also available in Vagrant Cloud  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>