<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SRE on Home</title>
    <link>http://example.org/sre/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SRE on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 17:42:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/sre/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Review</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sre/review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:04:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/sre/review/</guid>
      <description>This section contains reviews or summaries from exisitng literature.
1. SQL is no excuse to avoid devops @article{limoncelli2018sql, title={SQL is no excuse to avoid DevOps}, author={Limoncelli, Thomas A}, journal={Communications of the ACM}, volume={62}, number={1}, pages={46--49}, year={2018}, publisher={ACM New York, NY, USA} } Automation and a little discipline allow better testing, shorter release cycles, and reduced business risk.
Previous articles:
 “The Small Batches Principle,”Communications, July 2016), when something is risky there is a natural inclination to seek to do it less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myapproach</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sre/myapproach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 08:40:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/sre/myapproach/</guid>
      <description>What is SRE  SRE measures how reliable my serivice is from my customer&amp;rsquo;s perspective, not from my perspective. It seems most of the talks use current or historic data, logs, Why we do not estimate future data then ?  The reason is that usually you take generated logs, so it is hard to have a real-time observations. How to have real-time observations? how to estimate the future?    SLO  Defines a threshold, max or min value, for an SLI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>http://example.org/sre/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 12:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/sre/references/</guid>
      <description>This page present a list of references related to SRE.
Books   Beyer, B., Jones, C., Petoff, J. and Murphy, N.R., 2016. Site Reliability Engineering: How Google Runs Production Systems. &amp;quot; O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media, Inc.&amp;quot;.
 A online available version can be read from here.    Beyer, B., Murphy, N.R., Rensin, D.K., Kawahara, K. and Thorne, S., 2018. The site reliability workbook: Practical ways to implement SRE. &amp;quot; O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media, Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>